Guide to the Cornell Cooperative Extension Finger Lakes Grape Program records,
Cornell Cooperative Extension Finger Lakes Grape Program records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Cooperative Extension Finger Lakes Grape Program records, 1959-1994.
6773
Cornell Cooperative Extension
1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Printed Materials, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers pertaining to the grape programs, projects, grape pricing, correspondence, New York State Wine Grape Growers meeting items, crop committee reports, newsletters. and U.S. Tariff Commission Hearing report. Also slides of grapes and other activities.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Information about the program can be found here: http://flg.cce.cornell.edu
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers pertaining to the grape programs, projects, grape pricing, correspondence, New York State Wine Grape Growers meeting items, crop committee reports, newsletters. and U.S. Tariff Commission Hearing report. Also slides of grapes and other activities.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Cooperative Extension; Cornell Cooperative Extension; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station; New York State Wine Grape Growers
Subjects:
Grape industry--New York (State); Grapes.; Viticulturists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
See also New York State Wine Grape Growers records, #6714.
CONTAINER LIST
- Papers
  - Mechanical Prunning Project (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mechanical Pruning Demonstration (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Two photos from Taylor Wine Company, 4-14-69, possibly board of directors. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Crop Committe Reports (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Farm Business Analysis (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Progress Report to Concord Grape Research Fund, Feb 28, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - N.Y.S. Wine Grape Growers (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors Meeting 1978-80 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors Meeting 1974-77 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors Meeting 1972-73 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors Meeting 1969-71 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Board of Directors Meeting 1959-68 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - NYS Wine Grape Growers-Tariff Commission (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Grape Pricing (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Labor Hearing (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Grape Mailings 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Grape Mailings 1970-71 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Grape Mailings 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Original Newsletters 1987-89 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Original Newsletters 1990-91 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Original Newsletters 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Original Newsletters 1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Original Newsletters 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Binder of Grape Materials (Box 1, Folder 24, 25)
    New York Fruit Tree and Vineyard Survey, Grape Production, Trellis Construction, Fertilization, Disease-Insect Control, Farm Business Summary, Marketing, Mechanical Harvest
  - Photos and negatives of grape vines and vineyard activities. Some marked for publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Concord Grapes from Canada (Box 1, Folder 27)
    U.S. Tariff Commission Hearing, June 24, 1969
  - Slides (Box 1)
    Slides of grapes and other plants, presentations, disease photos, grape rot, vineyards, equipment, pests, Dr. Konstantin Frank, L. J. Edgerton, Milton Scott, mechanical harvest, cultivation, weed control, raspberries, dairy, field crops, Meier's vineyards, census and survey, other miscellaneous slides.